newswhip.com 2017-01-29

# NewsWhip - Privacy Policy

##### **NewsWhip Privacy Policy**

* * *

**1\. Introduction**

This Privacy Policy (“Policy”) explains what information we collect about you and why, what we do with that information, how we share it, and how we handle the personal information created, inputted, submitted, posted, transmitted, stored or displayed by you or your Agents when accessing and using our Services. Certain terms that are capitalized in this policy are defined and have the meaning applied in our Terms of Service.

For the purposes of this Policy, our “Services” refer to any services provided by the NewsWhip Group (including Spike, Insights, and/or any API), as more completely described in our Terms of Service. Each Service shall also include any Additional Services.

If there are any material changes to this Policy, you will be notified by email, through the Service, or by posting a prominent notice on our Websites prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices. Your continued use of our Services or Website constitutes your agreement to be bound by such changes to this Policy. Your only remedy, if you do not accept the terms of this Policy, is to discontinue use of our Service and our Website.

**2.**   **Information Covered By This Policy**

We respect and protect the privacy of visitors to our Website and users of our Services. This Policy explains the what, how and why of the personal information that we collect when you visit our Website or when you use our Services.

The personal information collected and used by NewsWhip Media Ltd., and its subsidiaries and affiliates, including NewsWhip US Inc. (collectively, the “NewsWhip Group” or “we” or “us” or “our”) is limited to the purpose for which our subscribers engage any member of the NewsWhip Group and other purposes expressly described in this Policy.

**3\. What this Policy Covers:**

  * The websites that link to this Policy, including:[ https://www.newswhip.com](https://www.newswhip.com/); and [https://spike.newswhip.com](https://spike.newswhip.com/) (collectively referred to as “Websites”).
  * The Services to which you have subscribed or registered. 

In this Policy, personal information means information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person. An identifiable person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identification number or to one or more factors specific to his/her physical, physiological, mental, economic, cultural or social identity. Except as described in this Policy, the NewsWhip Group will not give, sell, rent or loan any personal information to any third party.

**4.  ** **Personal Information That You Provide to Us or That We Colle**

**Account Information:  
**When you register for a Service, we ask for personal information such as your name, e-mail address, location, and credit card information, as well as certain related information like your company name. We also collect personal information such as an email address and a password from any individual authorized to use the Service through your Account as an Agent and/or administrator that you authorize to log into and utilize the Service in connection with your Account. If you sign-up for a free trial account, you are not required to enter your credit card information unless and until you decide to continue with a paid subscription to the Service. A third-party intermediary is used to manage credit card processing. This intermediary is not permitted to store, retain, or use your billing information for any purpose except for credit card processing on our behalf. We refer to any information described above as “Account Information” for purposes of this Policy.

By voluntarily providing us with Account Information, you hereby represent that you are the owner of such personal information or are otherwise authorized to provide it to us.

**Service Data:  
**We collect and store information that is created, inputted, submitted, posted, transmitted, stored or displayed by you or your Agents in the process of using our Services. Such information may include personal information or other sensitive information that you or your Agents choose to include. We refer to any information described above as “Service Data” for purposes of this Policy. All Service Data is subject to our technical safeguards as more fully subscribed in our Terms of Service.

**Cookies / Tracking Technologies From Your Use of Our Websites and Service:  
**Our Services and Websites use cookies for a variety of purposes. These cookies may provide us with information, including personal information, other information about devices and networks you utilize to access our Websites and Services, and information regarding your interactions with and in our Websites and Services. For detailed information about the use of cookies in the Service (including information about how you can control cookies) and Websites, please read and review our Cookies Policy here.

Web beacons, tags and scripts may be used in our Websites, Services or in emails. These assist us in counting visits to our Websites, understanding usage and campaign effectiveness and determining whether an email has been opened and acted upon. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by our service providers on an individual and aggregated basis.

We use Local Storage Objects (LSOs) such as HTML5 to store content information and preferences. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our Websites use LSOs such as HTML5 and Flash to collect and store information. 

**Log Files From Your Use of Our Websites and Services:**  
As is true with most websites and services, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol addresses, browser, internet service provider, referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and click stream data as well as certain personal information such as user name, user email address and other information that may be included in open textual fields. Our application log files are subject to the same strict data security policies and procedures as apply to the application databases for our Services. We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. We do this to improve the Services that we offer you, to improve marketing, analytics, or Website functionality.

**Analytics Information from Your Use Of Our Websites and Services:  
**We collect analytics information when you use our Websites and Services to help us improve them.

In our Services, analytics information may consist of the feature and function of the Service being used, the associated domain name, the username and IP address of your Agent (which may include personal information if the personal information was incorporated into the username) and additional information required to detail the operation of the function and which parts of a Service are being affected. The analytics information we collect may include elements of Service Data related to the function You or the Agent is performing. As such, the analytics information we collect may include personal information or sensitive business information.

**Communications With Us:  
**When you send an email or other communication to us, including support requests for our Services, we may collect the personal information that you provide us and may use it in order to process your inquiries, respond to your requests and improve our Services.

You and your Agents may receive occasional marketing communications regarding our products and services. If you would like to opt-out of receiving marketing communications from us, please contact us at [marketing@newswhip.com](mailto:marketing@newswhip.com) or follow the unsubscribe instructions included in our marketing communications. 

**Blogs and Public Forums:  
**Our Websites and Services offer publicly accessible blogs. You should be aware that any information provided in these areas might be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog, contact us at [marketing@newswhip.com](mailto:marketing@newswhip.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

**Subscriber Testimonials/Comments/Reviews/Feedback:  
**From time to time, we post subscriber testimonials on our Websites that may contain personal information. We obtain the subscriber’s consent to post their names along with their testimonials. If subscribers wish to update or delete their testimonial, they can contact us at [marketing@newswhip.com](mailto:marketing@newswhip.com).   

**Other Submissions:  
**We collect other information, including personal information, that you submit to our Websites or as you participate in certain interactive features of our Services, participate in a survey, promotion, activity or event, apply for a job, request customer support, communicate with us via third party social media sites or otherwise communicate with us. Any information, including personal information that you submit through our Websites could be visible to the public unless submitted to a secure area in the Websites.

**Personal Information From Third Party Services:  
**We also obtain other information, including personal information, from third parties and combine that with information we collect through our Websites and Services. For example, we may have access to certain information from a third party social media or authentication service if you log into our Services through the service or otherwise provide us with access to information from the service. Any access that we may have to such information from a third party social or authentication service is in accordance with the authorization procedures determined by that service. By authorizing us to connect with a third party service, you authorize us to access and store your name, email address(es), current city, profile picture URL, and other personal information that the third party service makes available to us, and to use and disclose it in accordance with this Policy. You should check your privacy settings on these third party services to understand and change the information sent to us through these services. For example, you can log in to our Websites and Services using a sign-in service such as Facebook Connect. This third-party service will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form. Facebook Connect (and other similar services) may also give you the option to post information about your activities on our Websites to your profile page to share with others within your network. Posting information about your activities on our Websites or Services on a third-party service is in your sole discretion and any such posting will be subject to the terms and policies of that third-party service and must also comply with NewsWhip’s Terms.

**Other Information That You Provide Us or We Collect:  
**In addition to personal information, we collect data and other information from visitors to our Websites and the users of our Services. This includes, among other things, anonymized information or aggregated data that the NewsWhip Group may collect about a group or category of Services, features or users while you visit our Website or access the Services. We define this information as Usage Data. Usage Data helps us understand trends in usage of the Services so that we can better consider new features or otherwise tailor our Services. In addition to collecting and using Usage Data ourselves, the NewsWhip Group may share Usage Data with third parties, including our subscribers, partners and service providers, for various purposes, including to help us better understand our subscribers’ needs and improve our Services as well as for advertising and marketing purposes. We may also publish Usage Data to provide relevant information about and to market the Services. Any personal identifying data, such as your name or email address, will not be shared to third parties as a part of the Usage Data. All Usage Data is anonymous.

**5\. How We Use Personal Information**

**General Uses:  
**We use the personal information that we collect for a variety of purposes including to:

  * Provide, operate, maintain, analyze, improve and promote our Services and tailor our Services to our subscribers’ needs;
  * Enable you and your Agents to access and use our Services;
  * Process and complete transactions, and send you related information, including purchase confirmations and invoices;
  * Communicate with you, including responding to your comments, questions, and requests;
  * Provide customer service and support;
  * Provide you with information about services, features, surveys, newsletters, offers, and promotions;
  * Provide other news or information about us; and sending you technical notices, updates, security alerts, and support and administrative messages;
  * Monitor and analyze trends, usage, and activities in connection with our Services and for marketing or advertising purposes;
  * Provide information to trusted service providers when such service provider requires this information to perform a service for the NewsWhip Group (any such service provider shall be required to comply with this Privacy Policy);
  * Investigate and prevent fraudulent transactions, unauthorized access to our Services, and other illegal activities; and
  * For other purposes about which we will notify you.

_Analysis of our Websites and Services:_

As indicated above, we use the information we collect (including log and configuration data) to understand how our Websites and Services are being configured and used, how they can be improved, and to develop new services, features and functionality. 

**6\. Sharing Personal Information**

**Third-party service providers:  
**We share information, including personal information, with our third-party service providers (such as credit card processors, managed hosting providers, sub-processors of Service Data, and technology partners) to provide the necessary hardware, software, networking, storage, and other services that we use to operate our Services and maintain a high quality user experience. We do not permit our service providers to use the personal information that we share with them for their marketing purposes or for any other purpose than in connection with the services they provide to us. 

**Other Services:  
**You may choose to make use of Other Services in conjunction with our Services. Other Services are third party products, applications, services, software, products, networks, systems, directories, websites, databases and information which our Service links to. When access is granted, certain information in your Account may be shared with the third party, including personal information. The NewsWhip Group does not control the policies and procedures of these Other Services even though the Other Services may be accessed via a link from our Service. This Policy does not cover the collection or use of information, including personal information, by Other Services, and we urge you to consider the privacy policies governing these Other Services. 

**Compliance with Laws and Law Enforcement Requests; Protection of Our Rights:  
**We disclose personal information to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims. We may also share such information if we believe it is necessary in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of our Terms of Service, or as otherwise required by law.

**NewsWhip Group Sharing:  
**We may share information, including personal information, with any member of the NewsWhip Group for the purposes stated in this Policy.

**Consent:  
**We may share your personal information with third parties when we have your written consent to do so or within the parameters of this Policy.

**7\. Choices**

If you are a subscriber to the Services or authorized as an Agent under a subscriber’s account to the Services and would like to opt-out of getting marketing communications from us please contact us at [marketing@newswhip.com](mailto:marketing@newswhip.com) or follow the unsubscribe instructions included in each marketing email. 

**8\. Accessing and Updating Your Information**

Subscribers may access, update or change Account Information they have provided by logging into the Service and providing such additional information where applicable. If you are a subscriber and would like to gain access to, or request deletion of information that the NewsWhip Group has collected as “data processors,” please contact us at [legal@newswhip.com](mailto:legal@newswhip.com). We will respond to such queries within thirty (30) business days. 

Individuals seeking access to, or who would like to correct, amend, or delete Service Data should direct their queries to the applicable subscriber of the Service acting as the “data controller” for such information. If requested to remove individual’s data by our subscribers, we will respond within thirty (30) business days. Technical limitations may restrict or eliminate our ability to remove or delete certain Service Data from all systems.

**9\. Location of Data**

**IMPORTANT: When you use the Website or Services, your data may be sent to the United States and possibly other countries.**

The NewsWhip Group may transfer, store, use and process your information, including any Personal Information, to countries outside of the European Economic Area (“EEA”) including the United States. Please note that laws vary from jurisdiction to jurisdiction, and so the privacy laws applicable to the places where your information is transferred to or stored, used or processed in, may be different from the privacy laws applicable to the place where you are resident.

**10\. European Safe Harbors**

We provide our Services to subscribers located within the EEA and Switzerland and, in so doing, process their Service Data, which may include personal information. We only access the Service Data where reasonably necessary to provide our Services (for example, to respond to support requests), as authorized by our subscribers, as disclosed in this Policy, or where we believe necessary for compliance with law. In legal terms, this means we are a data “processor” with respect to Service Data and our EEA and Swiss subscribers are the data “controllers”. As the data controllers, our subscribers are responsible for complying with applicable EEA and Swiss data protection laws and must assist their Agents and End-Users to exercise their data protection rights. As a data processor, we process this information in accordance with our subscribers’ instructions and have implemented security measures to protect against unauthorized and unlawful processing. 

The NewsWhip Group complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. The NewsWhip Group has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access and enforcement. 

If your principal location is in the EEA, we will ensure, pursuant to Article 25 of the Directive that, to the extent that any Service Data constitutes Personal Data, if Service Data is transferred to a country or territory outside of the EEA (a “non-EEA country”), specifically to the Unites States; then such transfer will only take place if: (a) the non-EEA country in question ensures an adequate level of data protection; (b) one of the conditions listed in Article 26(1) of the Directive is satisfied; or (c) We have ensured that the transfer is subject to adequate safeguards (such as the model contractual clauses designed to facilitate transfers of Personal Data from the EEA to all third countries that have been adopted by the European Commission (known as the, “Standard Contractual Clauses”) or adherence to the principles of the Personal Data Safe Harbors).

If you have questions or complaints regarding our Policy or practices, please contact us [legal@newswhip.com](mailto:legal@newswhip.com). 

**11\. Protection of Information**

We are committed to ensuring the security of your personal information. We utilize robust precautions to protect the confidentiality and security of the personal information within our Service, by employing technological, physical and administrative security safeguards, such as firewalls and carefully developed security procedures. For example, when you enter confidential information (such as login credentials or information submitted from within the Service), we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). These technologies, procedures and other measures are used in an effort to ensure that your Service Data is safe, secure, and only available to you and to those you authorized to access your Service Data. However, no internet, e-mail or other electronic transmission is ever fully secure or error free, so you should take care in deciding what information you send to us in this way.

**12\. Data Hosting, Transfer, and Retention**

Unless we expressly agree otherwise, the NewsWhip Group may host and process Service Data, including personal information, in the United States, the European Union, and in other countries through the NewsWhip Group and third parties that we use to operate and manage our Services. Whenever we process personal information outside of the European Economic Area on behalf of our subscribers located in the EEA or Switzerland, we will continue to afford it adequate protection in accordance with the requirements of the European Data Protection Directive 95/46/EC.

We will retain Service Data that is processed on behalf of our subscribers in accordance with the instructions received from our subscribers for as long as needed to provide our Services to our subscribers, subject to compliance with this Policy. We may retain and use other personal information, including personal information we collect as a “data controller,” as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, maintain accurate accounting, financial and other operational records, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements as described above. 

**13\. Children’s Personal Information**

The NewsWhip Group does not knowingly collect any personal information from children under the age of 13. If you are under the age of 13, please do not submit any personal information through our Services. We encourage parents and legal guardians to monitor their children’s Internet usage and to help enforce this Policy by instructing their children never to provide personal information through our Services without their permission. If you have reason to believe that a child under the age of 13 has provided personal information to us through our Services, please contact us, and we will use commercially reasonable efforts to delete that information. Subscribers are responsible for establishing policies for and compliance with applicable laws for the collection of personal information in connection with the use of our Services.

**14\. Business Transactions**

The NewsWhip Group may assign or transfer this Policy, and your Account and related information and data, including any personal information, to any person or entity that acquires all of our or substantially all of our business, stock or assets of, or with whom we merge.

**15\. Contact Us**

If you have questions regarding this Policy or about the privacy practices of the NewsWhip Group, please contact us by email at [legal@newswhip.com](mailto:legal@newswhip.com), or at: 

NewsWhip Media Ltd.  
Attn: Legal Department  
47 Merrion Square  
Dublin 2, Ireland
